Spalek, John M.; Papers ger106
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
John M. Spalek Collection1933-2010
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Spalek, John M.
ger106
7 cubic ft.
Professor of Germanic languages at the University at Albany, SUNY and main proponent of the German and Jewish Intellectual migr Collection who conducted oral history interviews.
Administrative History
John Spalek, Professor of German literature and one of the pioneers of what is today known as Exile Studies, was born in Warsaw, Poland in 1928. His father, Reverend Bronislav Spalek, was the co-founder of the Polish Baptist Church and in 1936, the family moved to Narewka in eastern Poland. There, Spalek witnessed the German invasion in September 1939, then the German withdrawal and the subsequent Soviet occupation. The retirement home run by his mother was confiscated by the Soviets. At the end of the war, the family headed for Germany. The Protestant seminary in Cologne, where Spalek’s father had studied theology more than 40 years earlier, helped them upon their arrival. For three years, Spalek studied the trade of cabinetmaker. On his 21st birthday, Spalek left Europe on a boat for New York. A family friend sponsored him through the immigration process and found him a woodworking job. But in 1951, he decided to go back to college. After completing an undergraduate degree in Spanish Literature, Spalek then embarked on post-graduate work in German literature at Stanford University. He completed his doctorate, and soon after was offered a teaching job at the University of Southern California in Los Angeles (UCLA). While teaching at UCLA, Spalek developed an interest in exile studies, a passion that drive him to devote his research career to the exploration and preservation of the exile legacy At that time, he was also working on a biography of émigré poet Ernst Toller and had to account for his exile years. He began a correspondence with one of the founders of exile research, Walter A. Berendsohn, living in Sweden, who urged him to begin similar research in the United States. At UCLA, and in the 1960s at the University at Albany, SUNY, he assembled and published the most comprehensive set of reference works devoted to exile writers in California and New York, along with his guide to archival materials, have become indispensable tools in German studies. In 1971, Spalek, was approached by the Deutsche Forschungsgemeinschaft (German Research Society) to begin a survey of papers on German émigrés to be found in the United States. It ended up as a 30-year project. Spalek and his associate, Sandra Hawrylchak, were largely responsible for locating and saving many of the papers, including many papers deposited at the University at Albany and the Deutsche Nationalbibliothek. The exile project documents the migration from Europe to the Unites States from 1933 to 1945, along with its intellectual accomplishments and its contributions to American society.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of two series: Series 1: Tape recordings; Series 2: Photographs.
The cassette recordings, unless otherwise indicated, were made by Professor John M. Spalek as background material in the compilation of his Guide to the Archival Materials of the German-Speaking Emigration to the United States after 1933. Additional tapes have been and are still being added to the collection. Recordings made by Dr. Eve Lee are designated as (Lee). There are no transcriptions. Dates and subjects of the recordings are given when known. Reel-to-reel tapes are part of manuscript groups in the German Intellectual Emigr Collection.
The major portion of the photograph collection was assembled during the early 1970s and formed the basis of a traveling "Exhibit on German Literature and Culture in Exile, 1933+", which circulated in the United States from approximately 1974-1978. Additional photos were added later to the collection.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is organized as follows:
Series 1: Tape Recordings
Series 2: Photographs
Series arrangement statement: SUNY will complete.
Acquisition Information
All items in this manuscript group were donated to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives.
Related Materials
Related collections in the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives can be found in the subject guide for Criminal Justice and Prisons.
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted.
Immigrants -- United States.; Refugees -- Germany.; Spalek, John M.; Lee, Eve.
- Tape Recordings, 1976-2010; 1
  - ADLER, ALEXANDRA, Undated (Cassette 1)
  - ADLER, HANS - Interview with Tina Adler about her father, Hans Adler., 2008 October 20 (Cassette 2)
  - ADLER, J.H., 2007 August 18 (Cassette 3)
  - ALBU, RUTH - recording made by Dr. Eve Lee, 1989 July 23 (Cassette 4)
  - ALBU, RUTH, 1997 June 9 (Cassette 5)
  - ALPAR, GITTA - (recording made by Dr. Eve Lee), 1989 October 14 (Cassette 6)
  - ALT, FRANZ - side A.; MONT, FREDERICK - side B, 1984 January 24; Undated (Cassette 7)
  - ALT, FRANZ - second interview, 2006 March 1 (Cassette 8)
  - ALT, FRED - Interview with HANSI ALT about her husband, Fred., 1982 November 24 (Cassette 9)
  - ANGEL, ERNST - Interview with Zvi Lothan on Angel, June 8, 2000, 1 cassette, 2000 June 8 (Cassette 10)
  - ANGEL, ERNST - Interview with Bridget Bogard about her father, Ernst Angel, 2000 May (Cassette 11)
  - ANGEL, ERNST - Interview with former student, Barbara Chesnut, 2000 March 17 (Cassette 12)
  - ANKER, HERBERT - Interview with Dorothy Anker about her husband, Herbert., 2008 March 1 (Cassette 13)
  - ANSCHEL, EUGEN - Interview with Eva Anschel about her husband, Eugen, Undated (Cassette 14)
  - ANSCHEL, EUGEN - Interview with Barbara Anschel Kaltenbach about her father, Eugen Anschel, 1995 August 20 (Cassette 15)
  - BACHERT, HILDEGARD - (recording made by Dr. Eve Lee), Undated (Cassette 16)
  - BADT-STRAUSS, BERTHA - Interview with Albrecht Strauss about his mother, Bertha, and his father, BRUNO STRAUSS., 1991 April 17 (Cassette 17)
  - BAER, RUDOLF, 1984 March 24 (Cassette 18)
  - BAER, RUDOLF - (recording made by Dr. Eve Lee), 1990 April 2 (Cassette 19)
  - BAMBERGER, CARL - Interview with LOTTE HAMMERSCHLAG-BAMBERGER about her and her husband, Carl Bamberger. - (recording made by Dr. Eve Lee)., 1989 November 13 (Cassette 20)
  - BARON, SALO - Interview with Tobey Gitelle about her husband, Salo Baron. - (recording made by Dr. Eve Lee)., 1990 March 27 (Cassette 21)
  - BAUER, FREDERICK, Undated (Cassette 22)
  - BELLAK, LEOPOLD, 1991 February 14 (Cassette 23)
  - BENDIX, WALTER - Side A; HIRSCHMAN, ALBERT O. - Side B, Undated (Cassette 24)
  - BERBLINER, KLAUS - Interview with Walter R. Berblinger about his father, Klaus., 2008 February 29 (Cassette 25)
  - BERG, JIMMY (JAMES) - Interview with Gertrude Berg about her husband, Jimmy Berg. - (recording made by Dr. Eve Lee)., 1989 August 11 (Cassette 26)
  - BERGES, MARTHA - Interview with Ruth Berges about her mother, Martha, and her father, SELIG (SEMMY) BERGES. - (recording made by Dr. Eve Lee)., 1990 January 6 (Cassette 27)
  - BERGMANN, PETER G. - (recording made by Dr. Eve Lee)., 1989 November 13 (Cassette 28)
  - BERL, ERNST - Interview with Walter Berl about his father, Ernst., 1982 November 22 (Cassette 29)
  - BERL-LEE, MARIA - Interview with her brother-in-law, Robert Lee., 2005 June 27 (Cassette 30)
  - BERLINER, BERNHARD - Interview with Gabie Berliner about her father, Bernhard., 2005 August 27 (Cassette 31)
  - BETTMANN, OTTO - (recording made by Dr. Eve Lee)., 1990 February 14 (Cassette 32)
  - BIEL, EGON VITALIS - Interview with Preston Bissinger on Biel, 1991 April 20 (Cassette 33)
  - BIEL, EGON VITALIS - Interview with Adrienne Wincor-Sternklar on Biel, 1991 March 21 (Cassette 34)
  - BLANKE, HENRY - Interview with Sonja Blanke about her husband, Henry. - (recording made by Dr. Eve Lee)., 1989 May 4 (Cassette 35)
  - BLUMENAU, FRITZ - Interview with Ruth Oberhnsli on Blumenau., 1998 August (Cassette 36)
  - BLUMENTHAL, FRITZ, 1990 November 11 (Cassette 37)
  - BODENHEIMER, EDGAR - (recording made by Dr. Eve Lee)., 1989 September 16 (Cassette 38)
  - BODENSTEIN, DIETRICH, 1982 November 30 (Cassette 39)
  - BOEHM, ERIC, 2001 August 24 (Cassette 40)
  - BORCHARDT, HERMANN - Interview with Frank Borchardt about his father, Hermann, 1996 June 22 (Cassette 41)
  - BORCHARDT, HERMANN - Radio Program about H. Borchardt, Deutschland Radio, 2005 March 1 (Cassette 42)
  - BRANDT, KARL - Interview with sons of Karl Brandt about their father., 2005 August 31 (Cassette 43)
  - BRANDT, THOMAS O. - Interview with Heidi Brandt about her husband, Thomas., 1992 January 2 (Cassette 44)
  - BRAUER, ALFRED - Interview with Hildegard Brauer about her husband, Alfred., 1991 April 18 (Cassette 45)
  - BRAUNSTEIN, JOSEPH - (recording made by Dr. Eve Lee)., 1989 November 15 (Cassette 46)
  - BRECHT, ARNOLD - Interview by Adrienne Ash., 1977 May 18 (Cassette 47)
  - BREINER, EGON, Undated (Cassette 48)
  - BRENDEL, OTTO J. - Interview with Maria Brendel about her husband, Otto. - (recording made by Dr. Eve Lee)., 1990 March 27 (Cassette 49)
  - BREUER, ROBERT - Side B of one: GLUCKSOHN-WAELSCH, SALOME on Senior Edition, 1984 March 28; 1981 January 8 (Cassette 50)
  - BREUER, ROBERT - Side B of one: GLUCKSOHN-WAELSCH, SALOME on Senior Edition, 1984 March 28; 1981 January 8 (Cassette 51)
  - BRODNITZ, FRIEDRICH - (recording made by Dr. Eve Lee)., 1989 November (Cassette 52)
  - BRONNER, GERHARD - (recording made by Dr. Eve Lee)., 1990 February 15; 1990 February 22 (Cassette 53)
  - BROWNE, MARTHA STEFFY - Side A; HAAS (HIRSCHFELD), DOLLY - Side B, 1984 January 16; 1984 January 17 (Cassette 54)
  - BROWNE, MARTHA STEFFY - Side A; KAHN, LUDWIG - Side B, 1984 January 17; 2001 July 23 (Cassette 55)
  - BRUNAUER, STEPHEN ROBERT - Interview with Michelle Wohlford about her grandfather, Stephen Brunauer., 2001 March 13 (Cassette 56)
  - BUCKY, GERARD - (recording made by Dr. Eve Lee)., 1990 January 27 (Cassette 57)
  - BUEDING, ERNEST - Side A; JAHRREIS, WALTER - Side B, 1982 November 23 (Cassette 58)
  - BULLING, ANNELIESE GUTKIND - (recording made by Dr. Eve Lee)., 1989 June (Cassette 59)
  - BUSCHKE, FRANZ - Interview with Marie Buschke about her husband - Side A; SCHARRER, ERNST - Interview with Berta Scharrer about her and her husband, Ernst - Side B, 1984 January 24; Undated (Cassette 60)
  - CAHNMANN, WERNER J. - "Zeitgeschichte in Lebensgeschichten"., Undated (Cassette 61)
  - CASTELNUOVO-TEDESCO, MARIO - Interview with Lorenzo Tedesco about his father, Mario Castelnuovo-Tedesco. - (recording made by Dr. Eve Lee)., 1989 August 3 (Cassette 62)
  - COPLEY, A. L. (ALCOPLEY, L) - (recording made by Dr. Eve Lee)., 1990 January 3 (Cassette 63)
  - CUBE, IRMGARD VON, Undated (Cassette 64)
  - DANTINE, HELMUT - Interview with Nicola Dantine about her father, Helmut. - (recording made by Dr. Eve Lee)., 1989 May 29 (Cassette 65)
  - DAVES, JOAN, 1982 January 7 (Cassette 66)
  - DAVES, JOAN, 1982 January 7 (Cassette 67)
  - DAVES, JOAN - (recording made by Dr. Eve Lee), 1989 August 10 (Cassette 68)
  - DISCHE, ZACHARIAS - Side B; MEYER, KARL - Side A, 1984 April 4 (Cassette 69)
  - DISCHE, ZACHARIAS, Undated (Cassette 70)
  - DISPECKER, THEA, 1982 January 8 (Cassette 71)
  - DOMBROWE, ERNEST - (recording made by Dr. Eve Lee)., 1990 February 23 (Cassette 72)
  - DREIFUSS, ARTHUR - Side A; FEHR, RUDI - Side B, 1989 May 13; Undated (Cassette 73)
  - DZUBAS, FRIEDEL - Interview with Malinda Hatch, close personal friend of Dzubas., 2010 January 15 (Cassette 74)
  - EBERHARD, WOLFRAM, 1981 (Cassette 75)
  - ECKARDT, WOLFGANG VON - Interview with Nina von Eckardt about her husband, Wolfgang., 2009 April 14 (Cassette 76)
  - EHLERS, ALICE - Interview with Maria Ehlers about her mother, Alice., Undated (Cassette 77)
  - EHRLICH, GERTRUD, 2008 May 29 (Cassette 78)
  - EHRLICH, OTTO - Interview with Edna Ehrlich about her husband, Otto - Side A; GURWITSCH, ARON. Interview with Alice Gurwitsch about her husband - Side B, 1984 January 25; 1984 January 26 (Cassette 79)
  - EINSTEIN, ALBERT - "Mein Glaubensbekenntnis", from L. Wronkow., Undated (Cassette 80)
  - EIRICH, FREDERICK - Side A; SPERLING, OTTO E. - Side B, 1984 April 5 (Cassette 81)
  - EIRICH, FREDERICK - Interview with Ursula Eirich Moeller about her father, Frederick Eirich., 2009 November 12 (Cassette 82)
  - EIS, OTTO (OSSO VAN EYSS) - Interview with Madeline Van Eyss about her husband, Otto., Undated (Cassette 83)
  - EISNER, HANS - Interview with Thomas Eisner about his father - Side A; RACKER, EFRAIM - Side B, 1984 March 14 (Cassette 84)
  - EISSLER, RUTH SELKE - Interview with Ellen Eissler about her aunt, Ruth Selke Eissler., 1996 February 2 (Cassette 85)
  - ELIAS, HANS - Interview with Thomas Elias about his father, Hans., 2008 September (Cassette 86)
  - ELIAS, HANS and ANNALIESE - Autobiographical interviews., 1979 (Cassette 87)
  - ELSASSER, WALTER MAURICE - Side A; WINTNER, AUREL, interview with Irmgard Wintner about her husband, Aurel - Side B, 1982 November 21 (Cassette 88)
  - ERDOES, RICHARD, 2006 May 30 (Cassette 89)
  - ESMOND, CARL - (recording made by Dr. Eve Lee)., 1989 May 30 (Cassette 90)
  - ETTINGHAUSEN, RICHARD - Interview with Elizabeth Ettinghausen about her and her husband, Richard., 2007 June 10 (Cassette 91)
  - FABRY, JOSEPH - Interview with Claire Bradley about her father, Joseph Fabry., 2001 March 12 (Cassette 92)
  - FALKENBERG, PAUL, Undated (Cassette 93)
  - FEHR, RUDI - Side A; ADLER, FRANZ - Side B, 1983 January 6; 1989 Mary 12 (Cassette 94)
  - FELD, FRITZ, 1984 June 7-8 (Cassette 95)
  - FELD, RUDY, 1984 June 7 (Cassette 96)
  - FISCHER, ERNST, Undated (Cassette 97)
  - FLOCH, JOSEPH - Interview with Karl Pallauf on Floch., 1991 February 8 (Cassette 98)
  - FORSTER, KURT E. - Side A; JURMANN, WALTER, interview with Ivonne Jurmann about her husband, Walter - Side B, 1982 January 2 (Cassette 99)
  - FOSS, LUKAS - (recording made by Dr. Eve Lee)., 1990 January 11 (Cassette 100)
  - FRANKL, PAUL, Undated (Cassette 101)
  - FRIDMAN, EVA JANE ne NEUMANN (daughter of Sigmund Neumann), 2008 April 9 (Cassette 102)
  - FRIED, JOHN H. E., 1986 April 3 (Cassette 103)
  - FRIEDLAENDER (FRIEDLANDER), WALTER A. - Interview with Dorothy Mindlin about her father, Walter A. Friedlaender., 1988 August 18 (Cassette 104)
  - FRISHAUF, STEVEN - Interview about his career and that of his wife, ELSE PAPPENHEIM., 2006 November 16 (Cassette 105)
  - FRITZ, KURT VON, 1981 January 29 (Cassette 106)
  - FUCHS, PETER PAUL - (recording made by Dr. Eve Lee)., 1989 December 23 (Cassette 107)
  - FURTH, DORI - (recording made by Dr. Eve Lee)., 1990 March 30 (Cassette 108)
  - GALIMIR, FELIX - (recording made by Dr. Eve Lee)., 1989 August 15 (Cassette 109)
  - GARAI, JOSEPH - Interview with Selma Garai about her husband Joseph Garai., 2009 December 17 (Cassette 110)
  - GERO, GEORGE, 1984 March 23 (Cassette 111)
  - GLAZ, HERTA - (recording made by Dr. Eve Lee) Side A; KRENEK, ERNST - Side B., 1989 October 7 (Cassette 112)
  - GLUECKSOHN-WAELSCH, SALOME, Undated (Cassette 113)
  - GOLD, ERNEST - (recording made by Dr. Eve Lee)., 1989 July 29 (Cassette 114)
  - GOLDBERG, SZYMON - (recording made by Dr. Eve Lee)., 1989 November 9 (Cassette 115)
  - GOLDNER, MARTIN, 1980 January 2 (Cassette 116)
  - GOLDNER, MARTIN - Interview with Andreas Goldner about his father, Martin., 2008 March 6 (Cassette 117)
  - GOLDNER, MARTIN - Interview done by Andreas Goldner with his father., ca. 1980 (Cassette 118)
  - GOLDNER, MARTIN and ELISABETH - Autobiographical interviews., 1982 March (Cassette 119)
  - GOLDSTEIN, THOMAS - (recording made by Dr. Eve Lee)., 1989 October 31 (Cassette 120)
  - GOLLAN, FRANK - Interview with Andy Gollan about his father, Frank. - (recording made by Dr. Eve Lee)., 1990 February 22 (Cassette 121)
  - GOSLAR, LOTTE, 1986 February 8 (Cassette 122)
  - GRAUTOFF, CHRISTIANE - Interview with Andrea Grautoff Valeria about her mother, Christiane Grautoff., 1994 January 20 (Cassette 123)
  - GRNBAUM, FRANZ G. - Interview with David Grnbaum about his father, Franz., Undated (Cassette 124)
  - GRUENEWALD, MAX - (recording made by Dr. Eve Lee)., 1990 April 2 (Cassette 125)
  - GRUN (GRN), EMIL - (recording made by Dr. Eve Lee)., 1990 February 24 (Cassette 126)
  - GRUNWALD, HANNA - Interview with George Grunwald about his mother, Hanna., 2008 May 3 (Cassette 127)
  - GUETERBOCK, HANS - Interview with Frances Gueterbock about her husband, Hans, 2007 December 14 (Cassette 128)
  - GUETERBOCK, HANS - Interview with Theo Van den Hout about HANS GUETERBOCK, 2007 December 18 (Cassette 129)
  - GUGGENHEIM, FELIX - Interview with Kim Guggenheim about his father, Felix, June 9, 1990; interview with Margarete Horlitz about Felix Guggenheim, June 29, 1990 (recording made by Dr. Eve Lee), 1 cassette., Undated (Cassette 130)
  - GUNDERSHEIMER, HERMAN - (recording made by Dr. Eve Lee)., 1989 November 7; 1997 August 4 (Cassette 131)
  - GUTH, EUGENE - Interview with Michael Guth about his father, Eugene., 2007 August 17 (Cassette 132)
  - GUTH, EUGENE - Interview with his daughter, shortly before his death in 1990., Undated (Cassette 133)
  - GUTTENTAG, OTTO, 1980 January 2 (Cassette 134)
  - GYRGY, PAUL - Memorial for Gyrgy at the University of Pennsylvania., 1976 March 11 (Cassette 135)
  - HAAS, Arthur, 2007 August 19-2007 August 20 (Cassette 136)
  - HAHN, FRED - (recording made by Dr. Eve Lee)., 1990 March 26 (Cassette 137)
  - HAMMERSCHLAG-BAMBERGER, LOTTE, Undated (Cassette 138)
  - HANNAU, HANS WALTER - (recording made by Dr. Eve Lee)., 1990 February 21 (Cassette 139)
  - HARNIK, HANS - Interview with Edith Harnik about her husband, Hans., 2006 February 22 (Cassette 140)
  - HASENCLEVER, WALTER - Interview with Marita Hasenclever about her older brother, Walter., 1979 September 2 (Cassette 141)
  - HECHT, OTTO - Interview with Rudolf Hecht about his father, Otto., 2002 April 21 (Cassette 142)
  - HELMERS, PETER - Interview with Mae Helmers about her husband, Peter, (recording made by Dr. Eve Lee) - Side A; ESMOND, CARL, (recording made by Dr. Eve Lee) - Side B, 1989 May 29; 1989 May 30 (Cassette 143)
  - HERZ, ALICE - Interview with Helga Herz about her mother, Alice., 1998 October (Cassette 144)
  - HERZ, JOHN H., 1980 September 19 (Cassette 145)
  - HILL, CLAUDE - (recording made by Dr. Eve Lee)., 1990 April 5 (Cassette 146)
  - HIRSCH, ELIZABETH - May 28, 1984, 2 cassettes; Side B of one: WALLACH, HANS, May 29, 1984., Undated (Cassette 147)
  - HORENSTEIN, JASCHA - Interview with Peter Horenstein about his father, Jascha Horenstein and mother, Rose Landver., 2006 May 17 (Cassette 148)
  - HORN, WALTER A., 1988 August 18 (Cassette 149)
  - HORNER, HARRY - (recording made by Dr. Eve Lee)., 1990 April 28 (Cassette 150)
  - HORSZOWSKI, MIECZYSLAW - (recording made by Dr. Eve Lee)., 1989 November (Cassette 151)
  - HULA, ERICH - Side A; Loewy, Karin, start of interview about her father, HANS RADEMACHER, and stepmother, IRMA RADEMACHER - Side B., 1984 January; Undated (Cassette 152)
  - HUTSCHNECKER, ARNOLD - (recording made by Dr. Eve Lee)., 1989 October 30 (Cassette 153)
  - HUTTON, LEONARD (HUTSCHNECKER) - Interview with Ingrid Hutton about her husband, Leonard., 1991 February 6 (Cassette 154)
  - ISENBURGER, ERIC, 1986 June 8 (Cassette 155)
  - JACKSON, FELIX - (recording made by Dr. Eve Lee) - Side A; ROSZA, MIKLOS, (recording made by Dr. Eve Lee) - Side B, 1984 June 28; 1984 June 30 (Cassette 156)
  - JELLINEK, KURT - (recording made by Dr. Eve Lee)., 1990 March 28 (Cassette 157)
  - JEREMIAS, GERALD (JERRY) - (recording made by Dr. Eve Lee)., 1990 November 14 (Cassette 158)
  - JOLLES, H., 1984 March 16 (Cassette 159)
  - JESSNER, FRITZ - Interview with Eva Sampson about her father, Fritz Jessner., 2008 May 4 (Cassette 160)
  - JESSNER, FRITZ and LUCIE - Interview with Kathie Hilliard (granddaughter of Fritz Jessner) about the Jessner family., 2008 June 21 (Cassette 161)
  - JESSNER, MAX - Interview with Sabine Jessner about her father, Max., 2008 September 7 (Cassette 162)
  - JESSNER, MAX and LUCIE - Interview with Peter Jessner about his parents., 2008 June 27 (Cassette 163)
  - JONAS, HANS, Undated (Cassette 164)
  - JOSEPH, ALBRECHT - (recording made by Dr. Eve Lee)., 1989 July 27 (Cassette 165)
  - JOSEPH, RUDOLPH - (recording made by Dr. Eve Lee), 1989 June (Cassette 166)
  - JOSEPH, RUDOLPH, 1997 June 9 (Cassette 167)
  - KAHLER, ERICH VON - Interview with Alice von Kahler about the Erich von Kahler correspondence, 1977 October 25 (Cassette 168)
  - KAHLER, ERICH VON - interview with Alice von Kahler about ALBERT EINSTEIN, Undated (Cassette 169)
  - KAHLER, ERICH VON - interview with Alice von Kahler about ALBERT EINSTEIN, Undated (Cassette 170)
  - KAHLER, ERICH VON - Interview with Hannah Loewy Kahler about her step-father, Kahler, 2006 March 4 (Cassette 171)
  - KAHLER, ERICH VON, 2006 March 9 (Cassette 172)
  - KALSER, ERWIN (FRANZ) - Interview with Konstantin Kalser about his father, Erwin, and his mother, IRMGARD VON CUBE, Side B: SIMONS, HANS, 1984 June 21; Undated (Cassette 173)
  - KALSER, ERWIN (FRANZ) - Interview with Konstantin Kalser about his father, Erwin, and his mother, IRMGARD VON CUBE, 1984 June 21 (Cassette 174)
  - KANN, ROBERT - Interview with Marie Kann about her husband, Robert., 1991 February 15 (Cassette 175)
  - KAPER, BRONISLAW - Interview with Irene Kearney on Kaper. - (recording made by Dr. Eve Lee)., 1989 June 6 (Cassette 176)
  - KAPIT, HANNA, 2004 April 26 (Cassette 177)
  - KATZ, H.W. - (recording made by Dr. Eve Lee)., 1990 February (Cassette 178)
  - KAUNITZ, HANS, 1991 March 1; 1993 August 18 (Cassette 179)
  - KESSLER, FRIEDRICH - Interview with Jack Radey and Ann Hubbird about their step-grandfather, Friedrich Kessler, Interview with Paul Bessemer and Jack Radey about their step-grandfather, Friedrich Kessler, 2008 March 2-3 (Cassette 180)
  - KLEIN, JACOB - Interview with Elliott Zuckerman on Klein, undated, side A. Side B: JAHRREIS, WALTER, end of November 23, 1982 interview, 1982 November 23 (Cassette 181)
  - KLEINSCHMIDT, HANS J. - (recording made by Dr. Eve Lee)., 1990 April 4 (Cassette 182)
  - KNIGHT, MAX - (recording made by Dr. Eve Lee)., 1989 September 16 (Cassette 183)
  - KOCH-WESER, DIETER, 1991 July 19; 2006 October 16 (Cassette 184)
  - KRBER, LILI - Interview with Viktoria Hertling on Krber, 2005 April 25 (Cassette 185)
  - KRBER, LILI - Interview with her husband, Erich Grave, side B. Side A: blank, Undated (Cassette 186)
  - KOHNER, WALTER, 1982 January 8 (Cassette 187)
  - KORDA, ZOLTAN - Interview with Joan Korda about her husband, Zoltan. - (recording made by Dr. Eve Lee)., 1989 May 9 (Cassette 188)
  - KORETZ, PAUL - Interview with Maria Wrigley about her father, Paul Koretz., 1997 June 16 (Cassette 189)
  - KORNEI, OTTO - (recording made by Dr. Eve Lee)., 1989 September 18 (Cassette 190)
  - KORNGOLD, ERNST, Undated (Cassette 191)
  - KOSTER, HENRY - Interview with Prof. Johanna Roden., 1978 March 11 (Cassette 192)
  - KOTSCHNIG, WALTER, 1984 February 18 (Cassette 193)
  - KRAMER, EDITH, 2004 May 17 (Cassette 194)
  - KRAMER, FRITZ - Interview with Eleanore Kramer about her husband, Fritz. - (recording made by Dr. Eve Lee)., 1990 January 3 (Cassette 195)
  - KRASNY-ERGEN, WILLIAM - Interview with Viola Ergen about her husband, William KRASNY-ERGEN., 2007 August 20 (Cassette 196)
  - KRAUS, WOLFGANG H. - Interview with Jon Kraus about his father, Wolfgang., 2009 June 10 (Cassette 197)
  - KRENEK, ERNST - (recording made by Dr. Eve Lee)., 1989 October 14 (Cassette 198)
  - KRISTELLER, PAUL OSKAR - Side A; MAHLER, FRITZ. Interview with Pauline Koner about her husband, Fritz Mahler - Side B, 1982 November 7 (Cassette 199)
  - KROMMER, ANNA, 2001 June 10 (Cassette 200)